that health insurance is an insurance
product that covers your medical expenses.
Health insurance is a contract
between the insurance company and the beneficiary or the insured. The insured
pays the PM
and in lieu of the PM, the insurance companies
cover the medical expenses of the beneficiary.
This product can be understood in many ways.
One way to understand
how it operates is through an
indemnity plan and the
other is a benefit-based or
indefinite plan. In this, the insurance company pays
two hospitalization expenses related to your health issues,
whether it is
cashless through the hospital
or in the form of a Prism plan.
You can click here.
Some examples of internet plans include Arogya Sanjivani
Kulwant Kavach and the insurance company that
makes internet plans which are company
specific. The
other one is Ethics Benefit Plan,
Friends Benefit Plan, when someone  A health
issue arises and the event
against which you have insured occurs.
On the occurrence of that event, the insurance company pays a lump
sum amount, which is a certain percentage of problems, which can happen in a
hundred percent.
Health insurance can also be understood in another way. The
other way of understanding it is
who designed and developed it. If any insurance
product is designed by IRDA or General
Insurance, which is Real Life Insurance,
or the Government of India,
then such products are post-
production and that is the
insurance company. Its design
parameters, its benefits, its
coverage will remain uniform. The other
type of health insurance is
company specific, as soon as the company
designs it, what
parameters will it have, which diseases will it cover,
what will be the solution, how much will be the waiting
period, it will differ from company to company. The
standard is the same in both a product and such specific
product. The
premium is decided by the company itself,
but the approval comes from IRDA,
friends.  In this product, the
premium is generally lower than insurance company specific products, the
coverage is more and
these are generally better for the public. The
health insurance policies available on our Voice Mail Seva portal are as follows: Arogya
Sanjivani, Karuna Kavach,
Karuna Rakshak, Insurance Company Specific
Health Indemnity Plans, Chapter
Delhi Insurance, and Personal Accident. Now let us
see
which companies are
offering health insurance products on CSC SPV's Digital Seva portal. These are
New India Assurance Company Limited, Bajaj
IFFCO Tokio, SBI General Insurance
Company, Reliance General Insurance, ICICI
Lombard, Future Generali, HDFC Ergo,
and United India Insurance. Along with this,
we will see
which health insurance products are already live on the Digital Seva portal.
These include Health
Suraksha Hospital, Delhi Cantt, Help
Medicine, Super Top Up Line, and Karuna Kavach of Reliance General Insurance.
Similarly, there is
Health-Wise Policy and Health Gyan
Policy of Reliance General Insurance. There is Arogya Sanjivani of SBI General Insurance.
Yes
Stephen Insurance and Arogya of ICICI Lombard.  Sanjeevani